# Kseniia Zaitseva

+381629378980 · resong@icloud.com · github.com/iamresong Novi Sad, Serbia

#### DATA ANALYST

Data Analyst with 1,5 year of experience in analyzing large data sets and data visualization in retail and wholesale to have business insights and making reports. I have experience in marketing analytics, using tools such as SQL, Python, Excel and Tableau. Expertise in analyzing customer behavior, sales trends, market dynamics, and supply chain performance. I know how to transform numbers into valuable insights.

#### **SKILLS**

Data Analytics
Data Visualization
Data Processing

Google Analytics HubSpot LookerStudio

SQL Excel Tableau Python, used libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DesignRush
Data Analyst
Jun 2023 - Present

- · Site analytics taking into account a large amount of data
- Collection, analysis and interpretation of data related to customer site visits and user interaction with it
- Tracking user activity on the site: monitoring visits, user actions, time spent on the site and other metrics.
- Create reports and dashboards based on the collected data to provide the business team and management with information about the performance of the site
- Website optimization based on data collected during analytics to improve user experience, increase conversions and increase efficiency

HMAX Beograd Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

- **Data Analyst**
- Wholesale analysis, identification of popular products, profitable product categories
- Customer analysis to understand preferences, buying behavior, and segmentation, enabling the development of targeted marketing strategies
- Inventory and supply analysis: optimizing inventory and supply management, forecasting demand, determining optimal inventory levels, and improving supply and logistics processes
- Pricing strategy analysis, optimizing pricing policies, explores competitive prices, and analyzes the impact of price changes on sales volume and profit
- Forecasting demand, production optimization, inventory, and supply chain management

MadWave Europe May 2022 - Oct 2022
Data Analyst

- Exporting and cleaning data as well as maintaining large data sets
- Retail analytics with using big data to optimize pricing, supply chain movement, and improve customer lovalty
- Gathering and analyzing data related to the performance of retail stores
- Creating reports and visualizations to summarize findings and provide recommendations on how to improve store operations or increase sales
- Reviewing financial records, interviewing employees, observing customer behavior, and performing other tasks that help gain an understanding of how well individual stores are performing
- Analyzing data such as revenue growth rates, inventory turnover rates, and profit margins, interpreting data and providing ongoing reports on a weekly and monthly basis

NOVATEK Aug 2020 - Apr 2022

### **Civil Engineer-Analyst**

• Development and optimization of algorithms and models for data analysis and business problem solving

- Documentary support for the implementation of an investment and construction project at all stages of its life cycle, as well as the organization of construction production
- Drawing up as-built documentation
- Making acts and drawings, calculation of estimates

## **EDUCATION**

**Novosibirsk State University of Architecture and Construction (SIBSTRIN)**Bachelor of Civil Engineering

2015 - 2020